# NIKHIL BHUTANI

Sunnyvale, California | (C) +1 (669)269 8166 | **Email**: <a href="mailto:nbhutani2@dons.usfca.edu">nbhutani2@dons.usfca.edu</a> | **Linkedin**: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/bhutaninikhi1991">https://github.com/bhutaninikhi1991</a> | **GitHub**: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/bhutaninikhi1991">https://github.com/bhutaninikhi1991</a>

Dear Recruiter,

I am currently a graduate student at the University of San Francisco pursuing Master's in Computer Science and seeking summer internship for summer 2020. I came across the job posting for the same and I personally feel that I will be able to bring something extra to the table due to past experiences and multifarious skills gained hitherto. As an experienced software engineer with expert knowledge in C#, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript/Jquery, SQL Server, Web Services and .Net Framework, I feel confident that I am the right person to help the organization reach the next level of success.

I offer 5 years of development experience, a strong aptitude for learning new technologies, and a proven track record of meeting aggressive goals. My most notable skills include:

- **Software Development:** I bring over 5 years of experience developing software for multiple clients in various environments. I possess solid knowledge of object-oriented programming and software development life cycle. I highly encourage the use of coding standards to improve the overall code quality.
- **Project Execution & Delivery:** I have been successful in developing and delivering projects from conception and design through QA and deployment both independently and as a team member.
- **Communication Skills:** I am comfortable communicating with technical and non-technical employees throughout the company at all levels in order to complete projects and achieve organizational goals.

Overall, I feel that my knowledge and experience as a software engineer with my passion for new technologies makes me the ideal candidate to meet your development needs. I'd be glad to discuss my abilities and background with you in more detail. Thank you for your time and consideration.

I have attached my resume for your ready reference and I look forward to meeting you for the summer internship position

Sincerely, Nikhil Bhutani

# NIKHIL BHUTANI

# MSCS Student at USF | Former Senior Software Engineer at Silicus Technologies

Seeking a position of a Software Engineering Intern. Utilizing exceptional software engineering skills, as well as experiences gained through relevant education, academic projects and 5+ yrs of work experiences.



nbhutani2@dons.usfca.edu

+1 6692698166

in linkedin.com/in/bhutani1991

github.com/bhutaninikhil1991

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Software Engineer Silicus Technologies

04/2018 - 07/2019

Pune, India

- Designed and developed an application using C#, ASP.NET MVC4 Razor View Engine, XML, Javascript, JSON, AJAX and jQuery to record the medical history of patients
- Developed restful web services to transmit JSON data over HTTP for web applications
- Developed rigorous test cases using NUnit to ensure bug-free
- Deployed and supported the application code across various system servers
- Created custom HTML emails for clients/in-house newsletters and invitations for distribution to our databases

# Senior Software Engineer Musafir.com India Pvt. Ltd.

10/2017 - 03/2018

Pune, India

#### Roles/Responsibilities

- Lead a team of 3 developers to direct the end to end application life cycle process with a focus on coding and debugging
- Designed and developed Rest APIs(application programming interfaces) for Android and IOS App and created reusable codes and libraries to facilitate smooth future usage

# Associate Software Engineer Cognizant Technology Solutions

10/2013 - 09/2017

Pune, India

#### Roles/Responsibilities

- Worked in a team of 2 engineers to migrate the existing web application to MVC framework
- Redesigned sections of the website to ensure a more attractive and user friendly experiences
- Modified design to create a responsive page using Bootstrap
- Designed database on SQL Server 2016 and development of different database objects such as functions, triggers, stored procedures
- Designed and developed functional dashboards using Highcharts JS that allows gaining deeper insights
- Provide web support via email, phone, and other electronic communications

# SKILLS

Google Cloud

# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

### Steganography(C#/Web Service(REST)/WPF)

Designed and developed a standalone WPF application that encrypts hidden information into an image, transmits it over HTTP and then decodes it. It works by replacing bits of useless or unused data in regular computer files with bits of different, invisible information. This hidden information can be plain text, ciphertext, or even images

#### People Tags(Java/HTML/CSS/SQL/JQuery/AJAX/Apache Maven)

Designed and developed a web application "PeopleTags" which is an interest network. It can track people of interest, organize them in collections, and tag posts with people or collections. It is something like customer relationship management (CRM) software, but with the more general purpose of researching people and collecting information.

#### Web Games(Java/JSP/JQuery)

Designed and developed hangman and mastermind web games with object-oriented design using inheritance, polymorphism, interfaces, and abstract classes

#### Lexer and Parser(Java)

Designed and developed a software that performs lexical analysis, parsing, byte code generation and interpretation

## EDUCATION

# Masters in Computer Science University of San Fransisco

08/2019 - Present Courses(GPA - 4.0)

San Francisco, USA

- Data Structures and Algorithm
- System Programming in C
- Object Oriented Programming
- Data Visualization